[
  {
    "questionText": "How does a dirty windshield affect driving at night?",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Having a dirty windshield helps to glare from oncoming traffic",
      "Lights from oncoming traffic can hit it and create a glare",
      "It helps deflect the light of oncoming traffic so it doesn't blind you",
      "It causes bugs to stick more easily to the windshield and block your view"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Lights from oncoming traffic can hit it and create a glare"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your low beam headlights enable you to see ________ feet ahead and high Beam headlights ______ feet ahead at night",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "150, 200-400",
      "250, 350-500",
      "50, 150-300",
      "100,200-35O"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "250, 350-500"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When an oncoming vehicle has their high beam headlights on at night, you should:",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "turn your high beams on",
      "look at the white line on the right side of the road",
      "look at the dotted line to the left side of the road",
      "flash your high beams"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "look at the white line on the right side of the road"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Visibility at night is limited. What action(s) can you take to ensure you are able to see as well as possible?",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Turn on the dome light While you are driving",
      "Keep the dome light Off you are driving. Dim the brightness Of your instrument panel. Check that all lights and reflectors are clean and in good working condition"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Keep the dome light Off you are driving. Dim the brightness Of your instrument panel. Check that all lights and reflectors are clean and in good working condition"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are some behaviors that may indicate an impaired driver?",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A truck swerves suddenly to avoid an unmarked pothole",
      "A sedan pulls to the side Of the road and turns on the four-way flashers",
      "A car brakes hard to hitting a deer crossing the road",
      "An SUV Weaves from lane to lane without using turn Signals"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "An SUV Weaves from lane to lane without using turn Signals"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are some ways the exact same road may look completely different from day to night?",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Pedestrians and bicyclists are more visible because they typically wear hivis clothing",
      "Your headlights cannot bend around curves",
      "Your headlights Can illuminate Over hills",
      "Animals are generally sleeping so you see significantly less of them"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Your headlights cannot bend around curves"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "At night, how should you adjust your following distance?",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Decrease it by at least seven seconds",
      "Increase it by at one second",
      "Decrease it by at least two seconds  ",
      "Increase it by at least ten seconds "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Increase it by at one second "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "To ensure other drivers see you and your truck at night: ",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "turn the dome light on to illuminate your Cab ",
      "keep your high beams on at all times ",
      "decrease your following distance so other drivers know you are behind them ",
      "use your tum signals for every turn or lane change so your intentions are always clear "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "use your tum signals for every turn or lane change so your intentions are always clear "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How is your vision different at night? ",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The sharpness Of itnages in front Of you increases ",
      "Your vision is no different at night ",
      "Visibility to the left and right sides becomes clearer ",
      "Your eyes struggle adjusting from light to dark or dark to light "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Your eyes struggle adjusting from light to dark or dark to light"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your eyes struggle adjusting from light to dark or dark to light",
    "chapterId": 13,
    "quesOptions": [
      "maintain a cab temperature Of 72-74 degrees ",
      "stop at regular intervals to rest or stretch ",
      "play loud, upbeat music ",
      "consume highly-caffeinated drinks "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A road is __________ anyone who uses the road, while a road ________ is the state of the road surface ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "user, situation ",
      "User, condition ",
      "Person, condition ",
      "Condition, user "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "User, condition "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Traveling through a work zone can present which of the following challenges? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Traveling at higher limits, Wide lanes without any pedestrians ",
      "Confused drivers, narrow lanes, construction workers on or near the road "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Confused drivers, narrow lanes, construction workers on or near the road "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What type of sign is posted in a work zone to give you advance warning of lane closings, construction areas, and workers ahead?",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Yellow, square-shaped Signs ",
      "Red, pentagon-shaped Signs ",
      "Orange, diamond-shaped Signs ",
      "Neon green, hexagon-shaped Signs "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Orange, diamond-shaped Signs "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What speed limit should commercial motor vehicles (CMVs) drive when on an off-ramp? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "CMVS Should travel at least 5 mph less than the ramp speed limit ",
      "CMVs should travel at 5 mph more than the ramp speed limit ",
      "CMV's should travel at the posted ramp speed limit ",
      "CMVs should travel at the same speed as the vehicle in form of them "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "CMVS Should travel at least 5 mph less than the ramp speed limit "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following are signs a parked vehicle might pull into traffic? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Exhaust is coming out of the tailpipe ",
      "You see the brake lights ",
      "The driver is looking over their Shoulder at traffic ",
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "There are people inside the car "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you see jacked-up wheels, a raised hood, or activated four-way flasher in the distance, what should you do to avoid the disabled vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Move one lane to maximize your space",
      "You Should pull up behind the disabled vehicle to offer assistance ",
      "Take the nearest exit and get back on the highway a couple miles down the road",
      "Put on your four-way flashers and Slowly pass the disabled vehicle On the right "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Move one lane to maximize your space"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are signs a driver may be confused or impaired? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Tapping the brakes to down. Proper driving ",
      "Slowing or stopping suddenly and without warning. Erratic driving "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Slowing or stopping suddenly and without warning. Erratic driving"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following actions can you take to identify hazards early? ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Use your mirrors to scan behind and to the sides of your vehicle. Look 12-15 seconds ahead of your vehicle. ",
      "Maintain three seconds of space between your truck and the vehicle in from Of you ",
      "Tune your radio to a local channel to hear any hazard warnings "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": ""
  },
  {
    "questionText": "In addition to recognizing hazards, you should always _________ to avoid a crash ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "plan ahead asking What-if-questions ",
      "tailgate another Commercial motor vehicle ",
      "drive with your four-way flashers on ",
      "Speedup and swerve around confused drivers "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "plan ahead asking What-if-questions "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your escape route involves driving onto the shoulder, you need to be ready: ",
    "chapterId": 15,
    "quesOptions": [
      "to set your down and maintain control ",
      "for the Change in road surface ",
      "to hit the gas ",
      "to crash into any briers "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "for the Change in road surface "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your fifth wheel isn't greased properly, it can: ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Disengage your clutch ",
      "create steering problems ",
      "crack the apron ",
      "snap the kingpin "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "create steering problems "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Backing under your trailer at an angle can: ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "cause the ignition to Shut Off ",
      "push the trailer sideways or damage/break the landing gear ",
      "keep the airlines from getting pinched "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "push the trailer sideways or damage/break the landing gear "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your service line is loose or damaged, you'll: ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "drain out your air tanks ",
      "all answers are correct ",
      "increase your Stopping distance ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "Suffer a serious leak When you apply the brakes "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When performing the tug test, when should you stop? ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "When spotter gives you the proper hand signal ",
      "As soon as the trailer brakes pop out ",
      "AS soon as you feel resistance from the trailer",
      "When you hear a squeak from your trailer tires "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "AS soon as you feel resistance from the trailer"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the safest way to lower and raise your trailer's landing gear in high gear? ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Face the trailer spin the crank handle around your wrist ",
      "Face parallel to the trailer and use two hands",
      "Face parallel to the trailer and rest one hand on the trailer ",
      "Face the trailer. keep your feet apart, and rest one hand on the trailer "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Face the trailer spin the crank handle around your wrist "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "HOW can you ease pressure on the fifth wheel locking jaws before uncoupling your tractor-trailer? ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Chock the trailer brakes ",
      "Lock the trailer brakes and back up gently",
      "Park on a slight when possible ",
      "Turn the pintle hook at a 90 degree angle"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Lock the trailer brakes and back up gently"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "HOW can you pull the fifth wheel release handle in a way that doesn't put yourself at risk Of injury? ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Pull on the handle with your dominant arm using a 2ig•zag pattern to the grip ",
      "Bend at the knees. keep your legs and feet Clear Of the rear tractor Wheels. square yourself up With the handle. and pull Straight out ",
      "Grasp the handle with both hands, brace your foot against the tires. and pull ",
      "Tuck you legs and feet between the rear tractor wheels to get better leverage"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Bend at the knees. keep your legs and feet Clear Of the rear tractor Wheels. square yourself up With the handle. and pull Straight out "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When positioning the converter dolly for coupling, you should roll the converter dolly up to the front of the rear trailer and stop when: ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "the fifth wheel is fully under the trailer apron plate ",
      "the rear trailer kingpin is about a foot from the jaw opening ",
      "the fifth wheel makes Contact with the front Of the trailer apron plate ",
      "you hear the pintle hook snap into place "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "the fifth wheel makes Contact with the front Of the trailer apron plate "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When preparing to couple a rear trailer to a converter dolly, the trailer height should be _______ the center of the fifth wheel. ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Slightly lower than ",
      "Perpendicular to ",
      "the same height as ",
      "Slightly higher than "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Slightly lower than "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When uncoupling the converter dolly, why should you never unlock the pintle hook with the dolly under the rear trailer? ",
    "chapterId": 7,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The trailer could drop ",
      "The dolly tow bar could fly up. possibly causing injury ",
      "You can unlock the pintle hook with the dolly under the rear trailer ",
      "The trailer could start to roll "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The dolly tow bar could fly up. possibly causing injury "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "In a manual transmission, the ______________ controls what gear the transmission is in ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": ["Accelerator ", "Clutch ", "Brake  ", "Shift lever "],
    "quesAnswer": "Shift lever "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When your vehicle reaches the maximum speed for a gear, you must: ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Pump the brakes ",
      "downshift",
      "upshift ",
      "Push the accelerator "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "upshift "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When double clutching is done correctly, and the RPMs are matched during the shift: ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The gears do not grind ",
      "It helps you wait for the 500 RPM change before Changing gears ",
      "It gives you time to determine what gear comes next ",
      "It enables to get in a rhythm with the engine "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The gears do not grind "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Downshifting early is a common error that may: ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Allow the engine to rev at IOW level, possibty causirvg the vehicle to Stall ",
      "Make the Clutch out forcefully ",
      "Cause the Clutch to burn ",
      "Make it to get into the next lower gear "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Make it to get into the next lower gear "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The purpose Of upshifting is to: ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Slow down the vehicle ",
      "Allow the vehicle to increase speed ",
      "Transfer power from the transmission to the engine ",
      "Match road speed With engine power"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Allow the vehicle to increase speed "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Proper, smooth shifting is important because if you shift before your vehicle is ready. ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Your entire tractor-trailer may jerk forward",
      "Your drive wheels may lock up momentarily ",
      "You could lose control of your vehicle ",
      "All answers are correct",
      "All answers are incorrect "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What actions negatively impact your vehicle's fuel economy? ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Sitting in Of a gear (causes the motor to bog down)",
      "using a heel-toe acceleration technique (causes the gears to Slip) ",
      "using double clutching (causes the RPMs to drop too low) ",
      "Downshifting too early (causes the RPMs to jump up) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Downshifting too early (causes the RPMs to jump up) "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "With an autoshift transmission, if the transmission is in the drive position: ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Only the low gears will automatically change ",
      "It will shift gears as needed based on speed and load ",
      "Only the top gears Will automatically change ",
      "You will use a button to control to Shift through all gears "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It will shift gears as needed based on speed and load "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the primary difference between a manual and semiautomatic transmission? ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The top gears automatically change in a semiautomatic transmission ",
      "The top gears automatically change in a manual transmission ",
      "A manual transmission uses electronic to help you shift ",
      "A semiautomatic transmission does not use a Clutch and gearshift lever "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The top gears automatically change in a semiautomatic transmission "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What does an automatic transmission use to change gears? ",
    "chapterId": 5,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Range control lever ",
      "Accelerator analyzer ",
      "Lever or button ",
      "Torque converter "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Torque converter "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If there is an imbalance Of ______________, a skid may occur ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Traction, wheel load and force of motion ",
      "Wheel load. tread depth. and brake pressure ",
      "tread depth. traction, and inflation ",
      "force Of 'notion. brake pressure. and tire inflation "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Traction, wheel load and force of motion "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are the most serious skids caused by? ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Tire blowouts ",
      "Driving too fast for conditions ",
      "Distracted driving ",
      "Controlled braking "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Driving too fast for conditions "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are the most common causes of a trailer jackknife? ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Over acceleration or overloading",
      "Oversteering or over braking ",
      "Overloading or oversteering ",
      "Over braking or Over acceleration "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Oversteering or over braking "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A _________ will occur when the drive wheels attempt to take over the front wheels, causing the rear of the tractor to swing out :",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Tractor jackknife",
      "Front wheel skid ",
      "All wheel skid ",
      "trailer jackknife "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Tractor jackknife"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is something you can do to help prevent a front wheel skid? ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Reduce your speed on wet or slippery pavement ",
      "Increase the pressure on your suspension system ",
      "Chain your tries in heavy rain ",
      "Reduce your drive tries inflation by 5-10 psi "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Reduce your speed on wet or slippery pavement "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Traction is needed to maintain directional control. You need traction in order to: ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": ["Load, to Seen and be Seen  ", "Brake, accelarate, tum "],
    "quesAnswer": "Brake, accelarate, tum "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What should you do if your brakes fail? ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Downshift and find an escape route ",
      "Hank your horn and flash your lights at all oncoming traffic ",
      "call 911 to have law enforcement clear the highway ahead ",
      "crank the wheel 180 degree and engage the emergency brakes"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Downshift and find an escape route "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you experience a tire blowout: ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Hold a steering wheel loosely ",
      "accelerate to overcome drag ",
      "steer into left most lane ",
      "brake firmly to slow your vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "accelerate to overcome drag "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your vehicle begins to hydroplane: ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "apply the brakes hard to come to a Stop as Soon as possible. ",
      "turn the wheel sharply to the right to guide the away from oncoming traffic",
      "Speed up to increase the traction between your drive tries and the road ",
      "slow down until contact with the road surface is reestablished "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "slow down until contact with the road surface is reestablished "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is one the main causes of vehicle rollovers? ",
    "chapterId": 16,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Driving to slow on ramps curves and turns ",
      "making slow lane changes ",
      "improper load securement ",
      "defensive driving "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "improper load securement "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Why is it important to be sure your fuel tank is topped off when adverse weather conditions are predicted? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It Can keep the electrical lines from becoming brittle and breaking easily ",
      "It can prevent carbon monoxide from leaking into your vehicle through the exhaust system ",
      "It can help ensure you do not run out of fuel and get stranded in a dangerous situation ",
      "It can help keep the appropriate ratio of fuel-to-oil in the fuel tank "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It can help ensure you do not run out of fuel and get stranded in a dangerous situation "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are some items you should have in your cab for your protection and safety when traveling during the winter months? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Extra food ",
      "Blankets",
      "Drinking water ",
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "Extra clothes "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What measures can you take to help prevent heat-related illnesses? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Dress in layers ",
      "Drink water frequently; avoid working in the direct sun; avoid heavy exertion "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Drink water frequently; avoid working in the direct sun; avoid heavy exertion "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Tire chains are most effective on: ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "heavy Snow ",
      "dry Surface  ",
      "Light, dry snow",
      "glare ice"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "heavy Snow "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Tire chains placed on ________ improve traction for downhill braking ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "any retreaded tires ",
      "the steer axle ",
      "the drive tires ",
      "the trailer wheels "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "the drive tires "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your engine does not start, Stop cranking it after ___________ seconds and check for problems with the fuel tank/lines, electrical systems, and battery ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": ["15", "20", "30", "60"],
    "quesAnswer": "15"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The tree basic causes of skidding and jackknifing are: ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "black ice, fog, and heavy snow ",
      "dry powdery snow, rain, and high Winds ",
      "Under accelarating, underbraking, and understeering ",
      "overaccelerating, overbraking. and oversteering "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "overaccelerating, overbraking. and oversteering "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If your vehicle breaks down in cold, windy conditions, what can you do to keep yourself safe? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Stand outside to the right the vehicle. also you can walk to the nearest gas station for help. ",
      "Stay in the vehicle cab and put on extra clothing and stay warm "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Stay in the vehicle cab and put on extra clothing and stay warm "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What primary factor(s) should help you determine what gear to select while traveling up steep grades? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The length of the grade ",
      "The weight Of the load on the vehicle ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "The steepness of the grade ",
      "all answers are correct"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When traveling on roads with sharp curves, how should you adjust your speed? ",
    "chapterId": 14,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You should not travel on roads with Sharp Curves ",
      "Reduce your speed by at least 5-10 mph",
      "Maintain a steady pace at the speed limit ",
      "Increase your speed by 5-10 mph "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Reduce your speed by at least 5-10 mph"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Why is proper space management so important? ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You can use cruise control more, resulting in more efficient fuel economy",
      "You'll remain calmer and more relaxed, helping to stay alert while driving  ",
      "You will be able to make positional adjustments when unsafe conditions arise ",
      "You will draw less attention from law enforcement  "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "You will be able to make positional adjustments when unsafe conditions arise "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you're driving your 70-foot rig at 65 mph in good weather conditions and minimal traffic, you should leave ______ seconds between you and the car ahead Of you ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": ["8", "10", "12", "15 "],
    "quesAnswer": "8"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you're being tailgated, what are some actions you should take to Stay safe? ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Quickly change lanes ",
      "speed up  ",
      "Tap your brake lights ",
      "Stay to the right "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Stay to the right "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How can you ensure a cushion on either side Of your vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Don't hug the centerline in drift to the left ",
      "Travel alongside other vehicles as often as you can to ensure they see you at all times ",
      "Stay tight to the right side of the road to put as much distance between you and oncoming traffic ",
      "Honk your horn if you notice Another vehicle within 5 feet of the side of your vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Stay tight to the right side of the road to put as much distance between you and oncoming traffic "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Minimum clearance distance for any overpasses you may encounter on your route is ___________ if your trailer is 13'6'' tall",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "16' - 16'3''",
      "15'6-16'",
      "14'-14'2'' ",
      "13'8'' - 13'10''"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "14'-14'2'' "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How does a heavy load impact the clearance distance below your trailer?  ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It reduces the clearance distance below ",
      "It increases the clearance distance below ",
      "It does not impact the clearance distance below your trailer ",
      "It reduces the clearance distance in the back but increases it in the front "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It reduces the clearance distance below "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When you are making a right turn, _________ before starting the turn. ",

    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Stop for at least Seven seconds ",
      "turn wide to the left",
      "Pull your tractor-traitor Straight into the intersection ",
      "Move to the leftmost lane "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Pull your tractor-traitor Straight into the intersection "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If there are two lanes available for a left turn: ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "make Sure you've reached the Center Of the intersection before Starting the turn",
      "be aware Of Off-tracking ",
      "always take the lane furthest to the right ",
      "all answers are correct ",
      "all answers are incorrect "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following signs might indicate a distracted driver? ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Reducing their speed dramatically to avoid with other vehicles ",
      "Changing their speed erratically for no apparent reason ",
      "providing adequate space ahead and behind their vehicle fat merging traffic ",
      "Maintaining their position in a single lane for an extended period of time "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Changing their speed erratically for no apparent reason "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you encounter a distracted driver who is on their handheld cell phone, what are some actions you can take to ensure your own safety? ",
    "chapterId": 12,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Move to the right (if you earl safely) to encourage the driver to pass you ",
      "Flash your headlights or tap your brake lights to got their attention ",
      "Attempt to make eye contact and motion for them to hang up the phone",
      "Hank your horn (electric to get their attention or air horn to warn them of danger) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Move to the right (if you earl safely) to encourage the driver to pass you "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Your ___________ is the distance a vehicle travels from the time you see a hazard until your brain recognizes it ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "perception distance ",
      "braking distance ",
      "brake lag distance ",
      "reaction distance "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "perception distance "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A CMV's components (brakes, tires, springs, etc.) are designed to work best when: ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "the vehicle is fully loaded ",
      "the vehicle is completely empty ",
      "traveling in adverse weather conditions ",
      "traveling through Curves and on grades "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "the vehicle is fully loaded "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How does traveling at higher speeds affect your CMV's total stopping distance? ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It decreases your total stopping distance ",
      "It decreases your reaction distance ",
      "It increases your brake lag distance ",
      "It increases your braking distance "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It increases your braking distance "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You should slow to at least mph below the posted speed limit when entering a curve",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": ["5", "10", "7", "8 "],
    "quesAnswer": "5"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "On a downgrade, your vehicle is working _______________  gravity, resulting in a(n) ____________ in speed ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "With, decreases  ",
      "against. Decreases  ",
      "Against, increases ",
      "with, increase "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "with, increase "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What danger(s) can foreign objects in the road pose? ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "They get caught between dual tires ",
      "They can cause damage to electrical and brake lines ",
      "all answers are incorrect",
      "They can be a danger to your tires and wheel rims "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What two factors are affected most by extreme weather conditions? ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Visibility and compatibility  ",
      "Traction and Visibility ",
      "Traction and position ",
      "Compatibility and position "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Traction and Visibility "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you unable to maintain a safe following distance when driving in heavy traffic, it's best to travel _________ surrounding vehicles",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "3-4 mph faster than ",
      "The exact Same speed as ",
      "3-4 mph less than ",
      "10 mph less than than"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "3-4 mph less than "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the result Of two or more convictions Of excessive speeding (15 mph over the speed limit)? ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "You will be disqualified for 60-120 days ",
      "You can incur potential fines and higher premiums ",
      "It will appear in your permanent diving record",
      "If at least one of the convictions in in your personal vehicle, nothing will happen "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "It is acceptable to use your cruise control: ",
    "chapterId": 11,
    "quesOptions": [
      "When driving at night or in adverse weather Conditions ",
      "When conditions are ideal, and only if your carrier allows it ",
      "during rush hour, when in heavy traffic, or while on congested highways ",
      "when you are tired or fatigued "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "When conditions are ideal, and only if your carrier allows it "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Visual distractions are: ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "only a problem for the people Who are not professional drivers ",
      "those that occur only immediately on the road in front of you ",
      "those that lure your eyes away from the road",
      "a type of distraction that you should focus your attention on while driving "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "those that lure your eyes away from the road"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "An example of a _________ distraction is eating a cheeseburger and fries while driving down the road",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": ["Visual ", "physical ", "Mental ", "Audible "],
    "quesAnswer": "physical "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is it called when you actually don't 'see' something, even though it's right there in your line of sight? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Highway hypnosis",
      "Comprehension blindness ",
      "Inattention blindness ",
      "PhysicaI distraction "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Comprehension blindness "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following statements is true about texting while driving? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Texting is allowable if you limit your answers to one word ",
      "Texting is almost as dangerous as talking on a cell phone ",
      "Texting only a by allowed by commercial motor vehicle drivers ",
      "The effects Of texting while driving are the same as being intoxicated "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The effects Of texting while driving are the same as being intoxicated "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "According to the FMCSA, which Of the following actions ma be permissible when driving a CMV? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Dialing a number while at an intersection ",
      "Answering a hands-free cell-phone by touching a single button ",
      "Holding a cell phone in one hand ",
      "Reaching for your phone to Check a message "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Answering a hands-free cell-phone by touching a single button "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Keeping both hands on the wheel in the ________  position will enable you to respond quickly to potential hazards, including distracted drivers",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "10-and-2position or 12-and-7 position ",
      "9-and-3 position or 8-and-4 position "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "9-and-3 position or 8-and-4 position "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you can't ignore a distraction, what should you do? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Take care of it at your next planned Stop or pull over ",
      "Take no more than five seconds to  handle it (tune radio, answer text, etc.) while driving",
      "If know you're getting an emergency call, you can go ahead and take it "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Take care of it at your next planned Stop or pull over "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are signs another driver is distracted? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct",
      "His or her vehicle is moving faster Or slower than other traffic ",
      "The driver is tailgating Other vehicles ",
      "The driver is ma king dramatic changes in speed for no apparent reason "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the best way to deal with a distracted driver? ",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Ignore the distracted driver and focus on the road in front Of you ",
      "pull in front of the distracted driver ",
      "Lessen the distance between you and the distracted driver ",
      "Create a safety cushion between you and the distracted driver "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Create a safety cushion between you and the distracted driver "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "You can help reduce distracted driving by: committing to not drive while you're distracted, watching out for distracted drivers around you, and:",
    "chapterId": 10,
    "quesOptions": [
      "recording the actions of other distracted drivers on the road  ",
      "relaxing when behind the wheel with deep breaths ",
      "Responding by managing distracted drivers once you spot them ",
      "reporting the actions Of distracted in your area to the FMCSA "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Responding by managing distracted drivers once you spot them "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Using your turn signals is optional when: ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "none of the above ",
      "returning to your lane after passing another vehicle ",
      "merging into the of traffic under 25mph",
      "Changing lanes when no one else is around "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "none of the above "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "On the highway, you should signal about ____________ feet before turning ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": ["500", "300 ", "250", "100"],
    "quesAnswer": "500"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If traffic ahead begins to slow, what should you do to alert those around you that you're slowing down? ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Flash your headlights ",
      "Drive onto the shoulder ",
      "Sound your horn ",
      "Tap your brakes "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Tap your brakes "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What can happen if you attempt to direct traffic by flashing your lights, blowing your horn, or using hand signals? ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You create a safer environment around your entire tractor-trailer ",
      "You can be found at fault for the mistake of someone else or it could cause an accident resulting in injury, damage. and potential liability",
      "You are only allowed to direct traffic if you wear a bright vest"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "You can be found at fault for the mistake of someone else or it could cause an accident resulting in injury, damage. and potential liability"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When approaching a pedestrian or bicyclist, always assume: ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "they are aware Of your presence",
      "you have the right Of Way ",
      "There are more pedestrian/bicyclists with them you cannot see",
      "they do not See you and could Suddenly move in front Of vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "they do not See you and could Suddenly move in front Of vehicle "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "From dusk to dawn, be sure your ___________are always turned on. ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Four-way flashers ",
      "headlights ",
      "turn Signals ",
      "brake lights "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "headlights "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which horn should you use when trying to communicate with others? ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Automatic horn ",
      "Bulb horn ",
      "Air horn ",
      "Electric horn "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Electric horn "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When is an appropriate time for you to use your four-way flashers? ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "When coming to a Complete Stop on a \"roadway or its Shoulder Or when slowing down unexpectedly\"",
      "At all crosswalks that are occupied by pedestrians ",
      "When exiting the highway "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "When coming to a Complete Stop on a \"roadway or its Shoulder Or when slowing down unexpectedly\""
  },
  {
    "questionText": "According to the FMCSRS, if you vehicle is stopped, you have __________ minutes to set out your emergency warning devices ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": ["10", "12", "20", "15"],
    "quesAnswer": "10"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "HOW can making eye contact help you communicate with others around you? ",
    "chapterId": 9,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It can enable you maintain full Control over your vehicle ",
      "It can help enforce Who has the right Of way ",
      "It can assist in confirming others awareness of your presence ",
      "Trying to make is distracting and never a good idea while driving "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It can assist in confirming others awareness of your presence "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Distance scanning helps you: ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "avoid abrupt Stops  ",
      "avoid radical speed Changes ",
      "all answers are correct ",
      "all answers are incorrect",
      "Identify hazards early  "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "As a general rule, look about _________ ahead of your vehicle ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "1-2 seconds ",
      "6-7 Seconds  ",
      "10-12 Seconds ",
      "12-15 seconds"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "12-15 seconds"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How often should you check your mirrors while driving? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Every 7 seconds ",
      "Every 4 seconds ",
      "Every 10 seconds ",
      "Every 20 seconds "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Every 4 seconds "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are potential hazards you must be aware of while driving? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Pedestrians ",
      "Stopped vehicles ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "Accidents ",
      "Animals ",
      "all answers Correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers Correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following scenarios could indicate a distracted pedestrian? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Someone looking both ways before entering a crosswalk  ",
      "Someone looking down while reading text on a cell phone ",
      "Someone looking Straight ahead at oncoming traffic ",
      "Someone making eye contact With you as you approach "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Someone looking down while reading text on a cell phone "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is a potential sign Of a distracted driver? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The truck behind you is Slowing down to make a right turn ",
      "The SUV behind Cut Off another driver and is now swerving and tailgating you",
      "The truck in front Of you Stays in its lane and maintains a consistent speed ",
      "The car in front of you has its cruise control set and maintains a consistent speed"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The SUV behind Cut Off another driver and is now swerving and tailgating you"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which type of mirror is designed to eliminate as much Of your blind spot as possible? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Fender mirrors ",
      "Plane (west coast) mirrors ",
      "Convex mirrors  ",
      "Rear view mirrors "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Convex mirrors  "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you need to see down the sides and towards the rear of your trailer, what mirror should you use? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Convex mirrors  ",
      "Plane (west coast) mirrors  ",
      "Fender mirrors ",
      "Rear View mirrors "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Plane (west coast) mirrors  "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When adjusting your mirrors, what should you See in the inside vertical edge of your plane (west coast) mirrors? ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A point on the ground 35 feet away ",
      "The trailer body ",
      "Part of the trailer ",
      "A point on the ground 30 feet away "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Part of the trailer "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When changing lanes, check your mirrors: ",
    "chapterId": 8,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "after you signal and as you begin the lane change ",
      "after you complete the lane change ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "Before you change lanes "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How does your trailer respond when you turn the wheel to the right while backing? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It drifts to the left ",
      "It drifts to the right ",
      "It pushes ",
      "You Should never turn Wheel While backing "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It drifts to the left "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is a key reason backing is so dangerous? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Backing tends to cause damage to accelerators ",
      "Backing gives limited visibility, you will always have a blind spot ",
      "Backing requires you get out of your tractor; you Could by another vehicle ",
      "Sticking you head Out the Window Can lead to Chronic neck and back pain "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Backing gives limited visibility, you will always have a blind spot "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the acronym commonly used to remember the safety check you should perform before backing? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "GOAL: Get Out And Look ",
      "FIRE: First Inspect Relative Environment ",
      "LAYER: Look Around Your Entire Rig ",
      "SAFE: Stay Away From Emergencies "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "GOAL: Get Out And Look "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you can use a spotter when backing: ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Responsibility for any incidents that occur transfers to the Spotter ",
      "You must agree on all hand signals before beginning the maneuver ",
      "Using a handbell cell phone to communicate With him/her is best ",
      "He/She Should be behind your vehicle at all times"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "You must agree on all hand signals before beginning the maneuver "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the backing techniques is fundamental in learning all other backing maneuvers?",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "parallel parking ",
      "Alley dock backing ",
      "Straight line backing ",
      "Slight-side jackknife backing "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Straight line backing "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the key characteristic to the alley dock backing maneuver? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Backing for a long distance (over 200 feet) ",
      "Backing Straight down an alley ",
      "Backing into a space alongside a dock ",
      "Backing while turning into a space that is 90 degrees to the truck "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Backing while turning into a space that is 90 degrees to the truck "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following statements regarding blind-side jackknife backing are true? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Your spotter should be visible at least 25 percent Of the time ",
      "Ending up with a greater than 90-degree angle is preferred ",
      "It is best to Stop every feet to Check your clearance or use the assistance of a spotter. if possible "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It is best to Stop every feet to Check your clearance or use the assistance of a spotter. if possible "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What backing maneuver should you use if the trailer did not wind up directly in front of the target? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Sight side jackknife backing ",
      "Blind side jackknife backing ",
      "Offset backing ",
      "Alley dock or curved backing "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Offset backing "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is something typically unique to loading dock areas you must watch out for when backing? ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Storage containers and dumpsters ",
      "unusual clearances around the dock and any nearby barriers ",
      "Straight pathways ",
      "Clearly marked paths "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "unusual clearances around the dock and any nearby barriers "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When backing in a parking lot, take note of the: ",
    "chapterId": 6,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Amount of fuel in your tank ",
      "Reading on your tachometer ",
      "position of the entrances and exits ",
      "Location Of the sun in the Sky relative to your mirrors "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "position of the entrances and exits "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the very first step you should take when starting a tractor-trailer engine? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Turn the ignition switch/key on ",
      "Apply the service brakes ",
      "Depress the Clutch ",
      "Apply the parking brake "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Apply the parking brake "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the appropriate cool down period for the tractor-trailer engine? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Between 30-60 minutes  ",
      "A cool period is not necessary  ",
      "It depends on the weather (temperature and humidity) ",
      "It based on the engine-type, nature of the trip, and cargo hauled"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It based on the engine-type, nature of the trip, and cargo hauled"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When setting your tractor-trailer in motion, how can you tell the friction point of your clutch has been reached? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The friction point light will flash ",
      "Your RPMs remain the same for a full 5 seconds",
      "Your RPMs increase ",
      "Your RPMs decrease "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Your RPMs decrease "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "After stopping your tractor-trailer: ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Flash your emergency lights ",
      "Pump the brakes to Charge the air tanks ",
      "Engage the emergency brake ",
      "Maintain enough brake pressure to keep the vehicle stationary "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Maintain enough brake pressure to keep the vehicle stationary "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When testing your tractor-trailer hook-up, pull gently against the locked trailer brakes and stop when: ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Your tractor does not move for at least 5 seconds ",
      "reach between 100-300 RPMS ",
      "Your trailer brake button pops out ",
      "You feel the engine start to drag down "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "You feel the engine start to drag down "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What should you do if you are unsure what may be behind your vehicle while backing? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Inform everyone in the Vicinity that will be hacking up and they out Of your Way ",
      "Stick your head the window and back during entire maneuver ",
      "Check your mirrors and quickly anything can your path ",
      "Stop get out Of vehicle, and Check your path "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Stop get out Of vehicle, and Check your path "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What should you do if you cannot easily Correct trailer drift (your vehicle is too far out Of position) when backing your vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Pull up, the trailer, and Start over ",
      "Find Someone to back vehicle for you ",
      "Turn the tractor around and watch both mirrors ",
      "Get a qualified to help you get back on path "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Pull up, the trailer, and Start over "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is off-tracking? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "When the rear Wheels Of a trailer lock up, causing the trailer to swing around ",
      "When the rear Wheels follow a different path than the front wheels while making a turn ",
      "When the wheels of a tractor lose traction and the vehicle off the road ",
      "The amplification of side-to-side through the rear of the trailer "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "When the rear Wheels follow a different path than the front wheels while making a turn "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is essential for you to do when you're making a left turn in an intersection with multiple lanes? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Speed up before you make the turn ",
      "Start in the rightmost lane ",
      "Begin turning as soon as your cab passes the crosswalk ",
      "Signal no more than 50 feet in advance "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Start in the rightmost lane "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What factors will determine how much time is needed to get your vehicle up to speed to safely merge with oncoming traffic on an interstate? ",
    "chapterId": 4,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The length of the on-ramp ",
      "All answers are correct",
      "The weight Of load ",
      "The on-ramp's degree of turn "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "In order to put a commercial motor vehicle on the road, you must first: ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Ask a mechanic about the vehicle's condition ",
      "Perform a Short test drive to verify safe operation ",
      "Complete and sign a DVR ",
      "Conduct a thorough pre-trip inspect ion "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Conduct a thorough pre-trip inspect ion "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Before you inspect the engine compartment and front axle components: ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Close the hood ",
      "Remove the chocks from the wheels ",
      "Verify the parking brakes have been set ",
      "Put the vehicle keys in the ignition, depress the clutch, and start the engine "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Verify the parking brakes have been set "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What is the minimum tread depth for the steer-tire? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": ["6/32 inch ", "4/32 inch ", "8/32 inch ", "2/32 inch "],
    "quesAnswer": "4/32 inch "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When inspecting the brake assembly, you should ensure: ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The slack adjusters are snug and tight ",
      "The brake Shoes have at least a quarter-inch lining ",
      "Crease is dripping no faster than one drop per minute from the brake drum or pads ",
      "Air lines have more than four cracks "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The brake Shoes have at least a quarter-inch lining "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "After the initial 50-mile check, how often must you conduct additional on-the-road inspections Of the cargo securement and securement devices? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Each time you stop to refuel ",
      "Whenever a change of duty status is made, every three hours, or I5O , whichever comes first ",
      "Whenever you Stop for fuel or every I5O miles, whichnever comes first ",
      "If you are Stopped for a roadside inspection and tail "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Whenever a change of duty status is made, every three hours, or I5O , whichever comes first "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What are the only circumstances you are not required to inspect your cargo and load securing devices? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "1.if your load is sealed and you have been ordered not to open it ",
      "2.If your destination is less than 100 — air miles from your home terminal ",
      "3.If your vehicle is loaded in a Way that makes Cargo inspection impossible ",
      "4.If you are carrying hazardous materials ",
      "5.All 1-4 ",
      "6.only 1 and 3 ",
      "7. only 2 and 4"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "6.only 1 and 3 "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When is it appropriate to conduct a post- trip inspection? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The same exact time every evening, regardless of where you are ",
      "At the end of every work day ",
      "Right before 12 midnight, when your next day begins on your driver's daily log ",
      "Whenever it's most convenient, but before the start of next day "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "At the end of every work day "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What items should a post- trip inspection include? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Brakes. steering, and lighting ",
      "Only items known to be defective ",
      "The same items as the pre- trip inspection except for things affected by heat ",
      "Oil and tire pressure  "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The same items as the pre- trip inspection except for things affected by heat "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When do the regulations require drivers Of property-carrying CMVs to complete and sign a DVIR? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "At the start of their work day for each vehicle they intend to operate that Shift ",
      "Whenever a defect or deficiency is discovered or reported ",
      "When a Change Of duty Status is made, every three or every I5O miles, Whichever Comes first ",
      "At the end Of their working day for any vehicle or equipment they used during that shift "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Whenever a defect or deficiency is discovered or reported "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If the previous driver found defects and noted them on a DVIR, what must you do before operating that vehicle again? ",
    "chapterId": 3,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Talk with the previous driver to ensure defects were noted properly ",
      "Ensure that any items listed defective/deficient that may affect the safe operation Of the vehicle Were repaired ",
      "Master Diesel Technician must personally certify the vehicle is safe for operation ",
      "The original of the DVIR must be received at the carriers terminal "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Ensure that any items listed defective/deficient that may affect the safe operation Of the vehicle Were repaired "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A commercial motor vehicle's (CMV's) engine controls are used to: ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Start up and shut down the vehicles engine ",
      "Safely operate your vehicle ",
      "Help Steer, accelerate, brake, and park you CMV ",
      "Warn you When pressures or temperatures reach a dangerous level "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Start up and shut down the vehicles engine "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If your truck has a(n) _______ you must first turn the engine key to the 'on' position before engaging it ",
    "chapterId": 2,

    "quesOptions": [
      "Clutch button ",
      "Starter button ",
      "Cruise control",
      "Engine break "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Starter button "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which clutch position is required to start the engine or shift gears? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Disengaged aged ",
      "Engaged ",
      "Free Play",
      "Clutch brake "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Disengaged aged "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following is a yellow, diamond-shaped knob that allows you to activate the parking brakes? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Parking brake control valve ",
      "Trailer brake hand-control valve ",
      "Fo ot brake control valve ",
      "Trailer air supply valve "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Parking brake control valve "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Secondary vehicle controls: ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Are the Same in every vehicle ",
      "Assist you in safely operating your Vehicle  ",
      "Shut down the vehicle's engine in an emergency ",
      "Provide backup functionality to the primary controls "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Assist you in safely operating your Vehicle  "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If your CMV has a __________ , the Federal Motor Carriers Safety Regulations (FMCSR) say you must use it ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Seat heater ",
      "Fog lamps  ",
      "Seatbelt",
      "Cruise control"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Seatbelt"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which vehicle instrument measures the voltage in a vehicle's electrical system? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": ["Odometer ", "Voltmeter", "Exhaust pyrometer ", "Ammeter "],
    "quesAnswer": "Voltmeter"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What is a normal operating range for a CMV's oil pressure gauge? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": ["30-50 psi ", "15-30 psi ", "10-25 psi ", "5-15 psi "],
    "quesAnswer": "30-50 psi "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following warning devices help you to know when exhaust temperatures are abnormal? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Coolant temperature warning light ",
      "Pyrometer warning light ",
      "ABS light ",
      "Differential warning light "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Pyrometer warning light "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following warning devices indicates there is inadequate pressure in the air brake system? ",
    "chapterId": 2,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Low pressure Warning alarm/light ",
      "Coolant level alarm ",
      "Oil level alarm ",
      "Oil pressure warning light "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Low pressure Warning alarm/light "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The trucking industry is subject to regulations from which of the following agencies? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "U.S. Department of (DOI) ",
      "Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) ",
      "Bureau of Transportation Statistics (BTS) ",
      "Bureau Of Safety and Environmental Enforcement (BSEE) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations (FMCSRs) establish basic safety rules and standards for: ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "only motor carriers and CMVs ",
      "all answers are correct",
      "Motor carriers ",
      "Commercial motor vehicles (CMA'S) ",
      "All answers are correct, except tolls ",
      "highway tolls",
      "drivers and Other employees of motor carriers "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct, except tolls "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "In order to obtain your commercial driver's license (COL), you must first: ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Have all restrictions removed from your personal driver'S license ",
      "Be at least 15-years Old ",
      "Get an endorsement for passenger carrying vehicles ",
      "Obtain a commercial learner permit (CLP) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Obtain a commercial learner permit (CLP) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following requires an endorsement on your CDL? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Manual transmission  ",
      "using an ELD ",
      "Air brakers ",
      "Double/triple trailers "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Air brakers "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "According to the FMCSRS, you are qualified to operate a CMV if you: ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Are currently disqualified from operating a motor vehicle ",
      "Are at least 15-years Old ",
      "Have only one current CDL ",
      "Have passed an IQ test "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Have only one current CDL "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following is considered a major disqualifying offense? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Following the vehicle ahead too closely ",
      "Violating an out-of-service order ",
      "Leaving the scene of an accident ",
      "Texting while driving a CMV "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Leaving the scene of an accident "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Prohibited alcohol use includes which Of the following? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Use during the eight hours following an accident, or until undergo a Post-accident test ",
      "Reporting for duty with an alcohol concentration Of 0.01 or greater ",
      "use during the eight hours before performing safety sensitive-functions ",
      "use while cleaning your windows and mirrors "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Use during the eight hours following an accident, or until undergo a Post-accident test "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following will result in you being removed from all safety-sensitive functions until you go through a return-to-duty process? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Failing an alcohol test ",
      "Testing positive for drugs ",
      "Refusing to take a required alcohol and/or drug test ",
      "All correct"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What part Of a combination vehicle is referred to as the 'power unit'? ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": ["Drive axle", "Duals   ", "Tractor ", "Fifth wheel "],
    "quesAnswer": "Tractor "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The federal size and weight limits apply to a national system of interstates commonly referred to as the: ",
    "chapterId": 1,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Federal Network ",
      "National Network ",
      "Limit Highway ",
      "Weight Road "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "National Network "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following vehicles are require to Stop at highway-rail grade crossings? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A tanker transporting a Division 2.3 Chlorine, a motorcoach carrying 19 passengers ",
      "A flatbed hauling lumber  ",
      "A refrigerated trailer full of temperature-sensitive produce "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A tanker transporting a Division 2.3 Chlorine, a motorcoach carrying 19 passengers"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If you're driving a CMV that is required to stop at railroad crossings, you must stop _______ the tracks: ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "within 75 feet Of. and no Closer than 25 feet to ",
      "Within 100 feet Of. and no Closer than 50 feet to ",
      "within 25 feet of, and no closer than 5  feet to ",
      "within 5O feet of. and no closer than 15 feet to "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "within 5O feet of. and no closer than 15 feet to "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are considered highway-rail grade crossing offenses? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Failing to have sufficient space drive completely through the crossing with out stopping ",
      "Having tire tread less than 4/32 of an inch On your drive tires ",
      "Inoperative brake lights ",
      "Operating a CMV during an out-ot- service order "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Failing to have sufficient space drive completely through the crossing with out stopping "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If convicted of a highway-rail grade crossing offense while operating a CMV for the third time in less than three years, what is the disqualification period? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": ["60 days ", "1 year ", "180 days ", "90 days "],
    "quesAnswer": "1 year"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A round, yellow sing with a large \"X\" and the letters \"RR\" accompanied by a smaller rectangular sign that reads \"EXEMPT\" means: ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all vehicles are exempt from having to Stop at there tracks at all times ",
      "this railroad track is abandoned, or its use has been discontinued ",
      "a stop is not required except when a train is approaching the crossing ",
      "a stop is still required but you can be closer than I5 feet from the tracks "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "a stop is not required except when a train is approaching the crossing "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "How can you tell if there are multiple tracks at a single crossing? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The number is located on each of the red and white striped gate arms ",
      "A sign indicating the number of tracks will on the post below the crossbuck ",
      "A yellow diamond-shaped Sign will Show an image With the correct number Of tracks ",
      "The number will be painted white in the pavement leading up to the tracks "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A sign indicating the number of tracks will on the post below the crossbuck "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "It takes approximately for a 53-foot, 80,000-pound tractor-trailer to cross a single railroad track ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": ["8 seconds ", "14 seconds ", "10 seconds ", "12 seconds "],
    "quesAnswer": "14 seconds "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What should you do if the warning lights at a crossing begin to flash after you have started to cross the tracks? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Maintain your speed and keep moving forward ",
      "Shift to a higher gear to get over the tracks quicker ",
      "Stop where you are until the train passes ",
      "Back up enough to clear the gate arm if it is safe to do so "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Maintain your speed and keep moving forward "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If your vehicle gets stuck on railroad tracks, what should be your very first step? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Put the vehicle in neutral and activate your four way flashers ",
      "Call the posted emergency telephone number ",
      "Get out Of the vehicle immediately ",
      "Wait in your vehicle until help arrives "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Get out Of the vehicle immediately "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Who should you call first if your vehicle stalls out on railroad tracks? ",
    "chapterId": 17,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Mechanic ",
      "Dispatch ",
      "Emergency number posted or 911 ",
      "Supervisor "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Emergency number posted or 911 "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When looking over the suspension system, you need to check for cracked, loose, or: ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "broken spring hangers ",
      "damaged u -bolts ",
      "damaged torque rods ",
      "all answers are correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The suspension system allows the axles to move up and down in response to ground changes without seriously affecting the load. _____________allows the stress Of road shocks to be distributed evenly throughout the frame ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Securing the suspension System at points spread throughOut the frame ",
      "Driving at 55 mph ",
      "Switching lanes regularly ",
      "Securing the suspension points directly Above each set of wheels "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Securing the suspension System at points spread throughOut the frame "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If your exhaust temperature is too high, what can get damaged?  ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": ["Aftercooler, Alternator ", "Engine, Turbocharger "],
    "quesAnswer": "Engine, Turbocharger "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The lubrication system lubricates, cools, and cleans the: ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": ["Engine ", "drive train ", "Brakes ", "Exhaust "],
    "quesAnswer": "Engine "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "As part Of an Oil change, the condition of the ___________  should be addressed. This item can help prolong the life Of the engine by removing contaminants as oil passes through it ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": ["Filter ", "Dipstick ", "Oil ", "Cap "],
    "quesAnswer": "Filter "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The is a series Of connected mechanical parts which take the power generated by the engine and applies it to the tractor's drive wheels ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": ["drive train ", "accelerator ", "Clutch ", "kingpin "],
    "quesAnswer": "drive train "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A defect in the braking system can interfere with a vehicle's ability to: ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Slow down or Stop ",
      "steer properly ",
      "Shift into gear ",
      "accelerate "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Slow down or Stop "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which system connects the tractor and trailer? ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Coupling system ",
      "Suspension System ",
      "Kingpin system ",
      "Transmission system "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Coupling system "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When checking the coupling system, you need to: ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Check the reading; Check the differential for loose Wire connections ",
      "Check the kingpin for excessive cracks. bending, or wear Check the fifth Wheel for cracks. breaks. security, and grease "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Check the kingpin for excessive cracks. bending, or wear Check the fifth Wheel for cracks. breaks. security, and grease "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "To keep vehicle systems in good operating condition: ",
    "chapterId": 18,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You should be aware Of your vehicle's condition at all times ",
      "pay attention to your senses: Sights. Sounds, smells, and/or the feel Of the vehicle Can indicated a potential problem ",
      "report vehicle defects and deficiencies that you cannot fix to your company ",
      "all answers are Correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How can you prepare for and pass roadside inspections? ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Plan your routes to avoid weigh stations ",
      "DO thorough inspections, keep paperwork in order and keep your vehicle well-maintained ",
      "When you notice a problem with your vehicle, ignore it.  "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "DO thorough inspections, keep paperwork in order and keep your vehicle well-maintained "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You need to keep your record of duty status current to your last change of duty to avoid a violation. This includes today's current activity and the previous ________________ consecutive days, which must be in your possession and available for inspection while on duty",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": ["7", "4", "5", "6"],
    "quesAnswer": "7"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Who is responsible for knowing how to execute the correct method Of transfer, and display or print logs on an Electronic logging Device (ELD)? ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The driver  ",
      "The inspecting Officer ",
      "The dispatcher ",
      "The carrier "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The driver  "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You, the driver, can be placed out of service during a roadside inspection if you: ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "are under the influence of drugs ",
      "Are driving while Sick ",
      "are keeping a false log ",
      "all answers are correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Your vehicle can be placed out Of service for: ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "having an intoxicated driver ",
      "a malfunctioning Electronic Device 'ECO) ",
      "having steer tires with a tread depth of 7/32 Of an inch ",
      "defects in the brake systems "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "defects in the brake systems "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following statements about the roadside inspection process is true? ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You cannot fix any problems found during the inspection. You must Contact carriers for a service call ",
      "Inspectors Will place a vehicle out Of service if they determine it to be unsafe or in violation Of safety regulations ",
      "One of the most common vehicle violation is a missing warning triangle ",
      "If using an electronic log, the Officer will verify device is mounted properly under the hood and that the driver has completed logs for the previous 14 days. "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Inspectors Will place a vehicle out Of service if they determine it to be unsafe or in violation Of safety regulations "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "After the vehicle inspection, inspectors will want to look at your CDL, record of duty Status, vehicle registration, fuel license, and: ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "accident history for the past year ",
      "shipping papers ",
      "Insurance card",
      "fuel receipts "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "shipping papers "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following statements about inspection reports is true? ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The inspector will download a digital copy of the report to your ELD ",
      "You are required to tum in the report to your carrier when you get to the next terminal or facility (or send to your motor Carrier Within 24 hours) ",
      "You will only get a report if problems Were found ",
      "Your carrier needs to address any problems with your vehicle and return the form to the issuing agency within 25 business days "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "You are required to tum in the report to your carrier when you get to the next terminal or facility (or send to your motor Carrier Within 24 hours) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When you pass an inspection and receive a CVSA decal, how long will it be valid? ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": ["3 months", "1 month  ", "2 months ", "4 months "],
    "quesAnswer": "3 months"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A driver's first violation Of an out-of-service order carriers the following penalty: ",
    "chapterId": 19,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Disqualification for one to five years ",
      "Disqualification for three to five years ",
      "Disqualification for 180 days to one year ",
      "Written warning "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Disqualification for 180 days to one year "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Adding engine Oil to your CMV is part Of: ",
    "chapterId": 20,
    "quesOptions": [
      "unscheduled preventive maintenance ",
      "Routine servicing ",
      "unroutine servicing ",
      "unscheduled repair "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Routine servicing "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You can keep your vehicle's components in good working order by: ",
    "chapterId": 20,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "detecting maintenance and repair needs as you and referring them to the correct place for handling ",
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "performing thorough pre-trip and post-trip making Sure you Check all pertinent Components each time you do inspection ",
      "verifying an annual vehicle inspection has been conducted on the vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Your responsibilities when it comes to actual maintenance will depend on your company's policy. Most companies expect you to fix simple problems such as ____________ but do not expect or want you to make other repairs ",
    "chapterId": 20,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Performing an engine tune up ",
      "Aligning the Wheels ",
      "replacing the brake line ",
      "changing out a light "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "changing out a light "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "According to the FMCSRS (Sec. 392.9), during the first SO miles of a trip, what must you check? ",
    "chapterId": 20,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The vehicle cargo and load-securing devices ",
      "The air pressure in each tire ",
      "The coupling devices ",
      "The oil level in the engine "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The vehicle cargo and load-securing devices "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following are additional expenses an incapacitated vehicle may incur? ",
    "chapterId": 20,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "Cost of renting another vehicle ",
      "Late delivery charges ",
      "Cost Of towing ",
      "Driver Wages meals, and lodgings "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The kind of tiedown you choose depends on the type of load you need to secure. Which tiedown is used in conjunction with a ratchet or winch-type assembly to increase the tension and eliminate any slack? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": ["Rope  ", "Chain", "Strap ", "Twine  "],
    "quesAnswer": "Strap "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which cargo securement device is placed on the exposed edge Of an article to distribute tiedown forces over a larger area of cargo than the tiedown itself, to protect the tiedown and/or cargo from damage, and to allow the tiedown to slide freely when under tension? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Edge protection ",
      "Friction mats ",
      "Logistics Straps ",
      "Dunnage "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Edge protection "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Always keep the center of gravity _______  as possible when placing your cargo ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": ["Low ", "far to the right ", "far to the left ", "high "],
    "quesAnswer": "Low "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Too much weight on a steering axle can cause: ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Poor traction, fuel economy high, reliable steering ",
      "damage to the tires or steering axle; hard steering "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "damage to the tires or steering axle; hard steering "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following statements about loading and unloading hazardous materials is true? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "B and C are correct ",
      "d) If you smoke during the loading or unloading process, you must Stay at least 10 feet away from any flammables or explosive ",
      "A and B are correct ",
      "C and D are correct ",
      "a) Any tools used in loading or unloading hazardous materials must be used with care so as not to damage Closures on packages on packages or containers, or to harm packages ",
      "b) packages containing any hazardous materials not permanently attached to a vehicle must be secured against any movement ",
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "c) the Shipper is responsible for Correct placement of place cards on your vehicle and maintaining them during "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A and B are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following is an important function served by the bill of lading? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "It is a receipt issued by the carrier to a shipper for goods received for transportation ",
      "It lists other Obligations assumed by the parties or to matters agreed upon by them ",
      "It is a contract naming the pames involved. specific rate or Charge for transportation. and agreement and stipulations regarding the limitations of the carriers common low ability ",
      "all answers are incorrect "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What date should be entered on the bill of lading? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "The exact date Of delivery ",
      "The day the form was filled out ",
      "The day payment is due ",
      "The exact date Of pickup "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The exact date Of delivery "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What does it mean when you (the driver) sign the bill of lading at pickup? ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are incorrect ",
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "You accept responsibility for the freight ",
      "The actual freight matches the type and amount listed on the bill Of lading ",
      "You are stating that your company accepts the contract terms "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Trailer seals are often used to deter theft and maintain cargo security ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Identifier seal ",
      "Indicative seal ",
      "Bolt seal ",
      "Barrier seal "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Indicative seal "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Open parking spaces in truck stops may be limited, but if you can, you should: ",
    "chapterId": 21,
    "quesOptions": [
      "park in the back Of the building under the cover of darkness ",
      "find drivers that will allow you to block them in for the night ",
      "park all the way in the back against the fence ",
      "park in well-lit areas, near the door, or near security cameras "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "park in well-lit areas, near the door, or near security cameras "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The burning of fossil fuels such as ______ releases nitrogen oxides into the atmosphere causing acid rain and smog ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": ["Oxygen, hydrogen ", "coal, gasoline, diesel "],
    "quesAnswer": "coal, gasoline, diesel "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "On average, an idling truck uses about one gallon of diesel fuel every; ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": ["Two hours ", "30 minutes ", "Three hours ", "Hour "],
    "quesAnswer": "Hour "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Engine idling impacts:  ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "fuel effiency your company's bottom line ",
      "How quickly a vehicle can accelerate or braking distance "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "fuel effiency your company's bottom line "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "How many states have idling laws? ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Just under one-quarter of all states ",
      "All States have idling laws ",
      "47 states have idling laws ",
      "One-half of all States "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Just under one-quarter of all states "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "In addition to select states, a _______ may also have idling laws ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": ["Fuel station, weight stations ", "County, village, City "],
    "quesAnswer": "County, village, City "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Auxiliary power units (APUs) are considered to be environmentally friendly and cost friendly, because: ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "they increase fuel consumption ",
      "they emit nitrogen oxides into the air ",
      "they use less fuel than an idling engine ",
      "they come standard in engines made after 2000 "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "they use less fuel than an idling engine "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Dirty air filters can:  ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Increase fuel efficiency add friction to the vehicle engine ",
      "allow impurities to damage the vehicles engine decrease fuel efficiency "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "allow impurities to damage the vehicles engine decrease fuel efficiency "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Long periods of cranking an engine can waste fuel, therefore you should ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "pump the accelerator or rev the engine after it starts to reduce the chances of engine dying",
      "crank the engine for upto two minutes, but no longer than that",
      "travel at the maximum speed once in motion to decrease the fuel use and air resistance",
      "stop and wait a couple of minutes before trying again if the vehicle's engine does not start after 30 seconds of cranking"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "stop and wait a couple of minutes before trying again if the vehicle's engine does not start after 30 seconds of cranking"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When transporting hazardous materials, you are required to carry _________ that is immediately available to you and any entity responding to, or investigating, a hazardous materials incident ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Shipping information ",
      "emergency response information ",
      "a COPY of the motor carrier regulations ",
      "first aid kit "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "emergency response information "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A report of a hazardous materials incident must be made by phone to the: ",
    "chapterId": 22,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Environmental Protection agency ",
      "Pipeline and hazardous Materials Administration ",
      "Department of transportation  ",
      "National Response Center "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "National Response Center "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When do the hours of service regulations apply? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "If you transport hazardous material in quantities large enough to require place cards if you drive a vehicle or combination of vehicles that weighs or is rated at 10,001 pounds on more ",
      "only when using an ELD to capture your record of duty status; only when using paper logs to capture your record of your duty status"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "If you transport hazardous material in quantities large enough to require place cards if you drive a vehicle or combination of vehicles that weighs or is rated at 10,001 pounds on more "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which task(s) would be included in the definition of on-duty time? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Loading or unloading a CMV ",
      "Repairing a disabled CMV ",
      "Waiting to be dispatched ",
      "Driving ",
      "All answers are correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What qualifies as off-duty time? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Time engaged in non-driving work-related activities  ",
      "Time complying with drug or alcohol testing requirements ",
      "Time when you are relieved of all duty or responsibility for performing work ",
      "time doing paid work for someone else "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Time when you are relieved of all duty or responsibility for performing work "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What's the purpose Of the FMCSA's hours-of-service regulations? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "To address the time it takes to service commercial motor vehicles by forcing carriers to log all repairs ",
      "to regulate how drivers and carriers deal with the time zone changes across the country ",
      "to prevent accidents or crashes caused by driver fatigue ",
      "to compile records of all recorded driving time across the country "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "to prevent accidents or crashes caused by driver fatigue "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following statements concerning the 14-hour limit is true? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Stopping for or taking a break extends the 14-hour limit. ",
      "A driver must be released from duty after 14 hours ",
      "An unexpected traffic jam that causes more than a 2 hour delay, Such as an accident, extends the 11 hour driving And 14 hour duty limits an additional 4 hours ",
      "the 14 hour period is consecutive it includes all on duty and off duty time acquired after coming on duty "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "the 14 hour period is consecutive it includes all on duty and off duty time acquired after coming on duty "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What is the 11- hour limit? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You must take a break for at least 30 minute at any time during your first 11 hours on duty ",
      "After 11 hours of driving time you must have at least 10 consecutive hours of duty before you drive again",
      "After you rest for 11 consecutive hours you may driver for 14 hours  ",
      "you must be off duty for at least 11 hours per day "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "After 11 hours of driving time you must have at least 10 consecutive hours of duty before you drive again"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Drivers of property-carrying commercial motor vehicles involved in interstate commerce have an option that allow them to reset their accumulated on-duty time. What is it? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "14 hour restart provision ",
      "34 hour restart provision ",
      "11 hour restart provision ",
      "20 hour restart provision "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "34 hour restart provision "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following would satisfy the 30-minute break from driving, required under the Mandatory Break provision? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "Completing load and payroll paperwork at restaurant",
      "Waiting to be dispatched ",
      "A lunch break ",
      "Resting in the passenger seat of a parked vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "After a stop for lunch you notice your ELD is malfunctioning. To avoid being in violation of the hours of service regulations, what do you need to do? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You need to begin manually logging your day from that point forward and for the next seven days ",
      "nothing you can avoid being in violation if you request your company send a request at the time of inspection ",
      "you need to manually log the current day and reconstruct the previous seven days ",
      "nothing a malfunctioning logging device is a valid excuse for not having records available during an inspection"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "you need to manually log the current day and reconstruct the previous seven days "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following information is required in the Remarks area of a paper log? ",
    "chapterId": 23,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Location (city, State) ",
      "Time Standard (time zone) ",
      "Rest periods (activity) ",
      "None: all information placed here is voluntary "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Location (city, State) "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following will help you maintain a healthy diet? ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Eat many different fruits and vegetables from your favorite color group daily ",
      "Eat a variety of and vegetables in a variety of colors daily ",
      "Look for refined grains when selecting bread, rice, or pasta ",
      "Drink at least two eight ounce glasses Of Water daily "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Eat a variety of and vegetables in a variety of colors daily "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What are some healthy snack choices you can take on the road with you? ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Chips, donuts. beer  ",
      "Unsalted nuts, vegetables. fruit "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Unsalted nuts, vegetables. fruit "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Beneficial physical activity includes: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "aerobic activities, balance and stretching activities, strength building activities ",
      "only non-weight bearing activities "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "aerobic activities, balance and stretching activities, strength building activities "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What effect can stress have on your body it is continues for a long period of time? ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "It Can lower your blood pressure ",
      "It can improve blood clotting ",
      "It Can cause Slowed breathing ",
      "It Can weaken your defenses and lead to disease "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "It Can weaken your defenses and lead to disease "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are signs Of fatigue? ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Feeling alert ",
      "Reduced reaction time ",
      "Making good driving decisions ",
      "Eyes focused "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Reduced reaction time "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A good way to fight fatigue is night by: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "driving during your down times",
      "adding variety to your sleeping schedule ",
      "establishing a regular Sleep and waking schedule ",
      "getting three of sleep each night "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "establishing a regular Sleep and waking schedule "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Upon entry and exit from your vehicle, you should always: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "maintain two points Of Contact ",
      "jump from ladders Or Steps if the distance is eight inches Or less ",
      "keep your back to the ladder or steps ",
      "maintain three points of contact "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "maintain three points of contact "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Safe work practices to remember when stopping on the side Of the road include: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "placing warning devices as required by the regulations ",
      "using your blinker when pulling to the side",
      "facing traffic When walking around your vehicle ",
      "avoiding soft Shoulders ",
      "all answers are correct "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Back pain is often due to: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "a lifetime Of bad habits and poor techniques  ",
      "consistently good posture ",
      "always using proper lifting techniques ",
      "eating a healthy diet "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "a lifetime Of bad habits and poor techniques  "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You should never share information about your load, pick-up and delivery schedules, or routing because it helps to ensure your: ",
    "chapterId": 24,
    "quesOptions": [
      "personal security ",
      "destination schedule ",
      "relationship with the receiver ",
      "awareness of your surroundings "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "personal security "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "If you leave the scene Of an accident and you are convicted of this offense, how long will you be disqualified from driving a CMV? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": ["One year ", "180 days  ", "120 days ", "60 days "],
    "quesAnswer": "One year "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Why is it important to move your vehicle (if you are able) to the side of the road if you are involved in an accident? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "so your four-way flashers are less distracting to discourage others from Stealing your cargo ",
      "To reduce congestion and delays to prevent additional accidents from occurring "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "To reduce congestion and delays to prevent additional accidents from occurring "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If you were involved in an accident and placed emergency warning devices four paces (or ten feet) behind your truck, forty paces (or 100 feet) behind your truck, and 40 paces (or 100 feet) in front of your truck, which type of road would you be on? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A two-lane road ",
      "A divided highway ",
      "A road with a sharp curve ",
      "A multi-lane highway "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A two-lane road"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Per the regulations, you have ____________ to set our emergency warning devices ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": ["2 minutes ", "5 minutes ", "7 minutes ", "10 minutes "],
    "quesAnswer": "10 minutes "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following is information you should document about an accident? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "All answers are correct ",
      "Any injuries or fatalities ",
      "Description of damage to vehicles and property ",
      "Description Of the event including weather and road conditions "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What conditions require post- accident alcohol and drug testing? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "An injury that requires minor first aid treatment on the scene ",
      "Only if two or more people are seriously injured ",
      "Damage to a vehicle that totals $500  ",
      "A human fatality "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A human fatality "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You must remain available for alcohol and drug testing if you are in an accident. Not remaining available for testing is considered a: ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "negative result ",
      "refusal to test ",
      "false positive result ",
      "prohibited action "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "refusal to test "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What are the four components required to make fire possible? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Ignition, oxygen, air, and contact with a heat ",
      "Fuel. heat. Sparks. and a fire tetrahedron  ",
      "Oxygen, wood, plastic, and a chemical chain reaction ",
      "Oxygen, heat, fuel, and a chemical chain reaction "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Oxygen, heat, fuel, and a chemical chain reaction "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If flammable liquids are on fire, which class of fire extinguisher would you need to put Out the fire? ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": ["Class B ", "Class A ", "Class C", "Class D "],
    "quesAnswer": "Class B "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Always use ________ to put out a tire fire ",
    "chapterId": 25,
    "quesOptions": [
      "a Multiclass fire extinguisher ",
      "a class A fire extinguisher ",
      "carbon dioxide ",
      "Water "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Water "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What type of inspection takes about 45 to 60 minutes and includes an examination of both the driver and vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Level-1 ",
      "Walk-around inspection  ",
      "Special inspection ",
      "Driver inspection "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Level-1 "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When you are the focus Of an inspection, you need to be prepared to: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "face steep fines and penalties ",
      "hand over documents and credentials ",
      "demonstrate your knowledge of the FMCSRs ",
      "argue with the inspector over his or her findings "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "hand over documents and credentials "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When your vehicle is the focus Of an inspection, it will be checked for: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "fuel efficiency (miles per gallon), last  inspection results implemented, drug test ",
      "unsafe Wear and tear mechanical problems, Non critical  deficiencies "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "unsafe Wear and tear mechanical problems, Non critical  deficiencies "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If the inspector found only minor violations, you: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Could receive a CVSA decal, could be placed out of service ",
      "may be allowed to continue your trip, might be given a fine "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "may be allowed to continue your trip, might be given a fine "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When would a CVSA decal be placed on your vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "If only minor violations were found ",
      "If you purchase one from the inspector ",
      "If no violations were found ",
      "If your vehicle is placed out of service "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "If no violations were found "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If your vehicle is placed out Of service, you: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "may proceed to the nearest Or repair Shop ",
      "are disqualified for ten years ",
      "may not drive the vehicle until the problem is resolved ",
      "may finish your route, if the inspector allows it "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "may not drive the vehicle until the problem is resolved "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "For your carrier, violations ad out-of-service orders mean: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "all answers are correct ",
      "lost revenue ",
      "delays in deliveries ",
      "poor CSA scores  "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When we communicate, 55% of the message comes across through: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "a loudspeaker ",
      "the tone We use ",
      "what we say: the literal (verbal) content ",
      "our body language "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "our body language "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When speaking with an inspector: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "be in an open position; relaxed. with your arms uncrossed ",
      "always be thinking of your response; interrupt if necessary ",
      "it'S Ok to be confrontational if you don't agree with his or her report ",
      "it's usually a good idea to start out with a well rehearsed joke "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "be in an open position; relaxed. with your arms uncrossed "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If English is not your first language, you still need to be able to: ",
    "chapterId": 26,
    "quesOptions": [
      "understand And communicated with universal hand signals communicate in at least one of the other top five spoken languages in the US ",
      "read. write. and speak well enough to make entries, Reports and answer questions from law enforcement;understand highway traffic Signs and Signals written in English. "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "read. write. and speak well enough to make entries, Reports and answer questions from law enforcement; understand highway traffic Signs and Signals written in English. "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Whistleblower protection laws are in place to protect you from retaliation if you: ",
    "chapterId": 27,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Refuse to operate an unsafe vehicle, report CMV safety violations ",
      "Are late for work on a regular basis; do not testify at a Violation hearing "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Refuse to operate an unsafe vehicle, report CMV safety violations "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A whistleblower protection complaint should be filed within ___________ days Of when the alleged violation occurred ",
    "chapterId": 27,
    "quesOptions": ["120 ", "90 ", "180 ", "60 "],
    "quesAnswer": "180 "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The key to coercion is that a clear _________ to the driver exist",
    "chapterId": 27,
    "quesOptions": ["Threat ", "Request ", "denial ", "Notice "],
    "quesAnswer": "Threat "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "In order for a violation Of the Coercion Rule to exist, three actions must have occurred including: the driver was requested to perform a task that would violate regulations, the driver communicated the violation that would occur, and: ",
    "chapterId": 27,
    "quesOptions": [
      "the driver was not threatened and no action was taken against the driver ",
      "the driver was reprimanded in front Of Colleagues ",
      "the driver refused to the commit the violation ",
      "the driver was threatened. or action Was taken against the driver "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "the driver was threatened. or action Was taken against the driver "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "To begin the coercion complaint process, a driver must file a written complaint within _________ days of the event ",
    "chapterId": 27,
    "quesOptions": ["30 ", "60 ", "90 ", "75 "],
    "quesAnswer": "90 "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which class of commercial driver's license do you need to operate a single vehicle with a CVWR of 26,001 pounds or more, or any such vehicle towing a vehicle not in excess of 10, 000 pounds CVWR? ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Class D license",
      "Class A license ",
      "Class C license",
      "Class B license "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Class B license "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What paperwork should you have with you that indicated title to the goods you are delivering? ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Bill Of lading ",
      "Operator's license ",
      "Trip report ",
      "Of duty status "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Bill Of lading "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If you discover a defect or deficiency during your post- trip inspection, you must complete a written report commonly referred to as a: ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Social permit",
      "trip report",
      "individual vehicle mileage report ",
      "driver vehicle inspection report (DVIR) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "driver vehicle inspection report (DVIR) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You should know what route you plan to take and identify before you depart ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "city maps ",
      "alternate routes ",
      "highway maps",
      "map grids "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "alternate routes"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A GPS designed for truck drivers includes information on IOW overpasses/bridges, and upcoming scales ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "weight Of your vehicle ",
      "your axle weights ",
      "route restrictions ",
      "the length and width Of your vehicle "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "route restrictions "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Per the federal requirements, the maximum gross vehicle weight is 80,000 pounds except where a lower GVW is dictated by the: ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "restricted route ",
      "bridge formula ",
      "highway bridge rule ",
      "tandem axle formula "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "bridge formula "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Estimating your trip time is crucial. It helps you: ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "comply with hours-of —service regulations; meet delivery schedules ",
      "overcrowded rest stops; comply with speed limits "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "comply with hours-of —service regulations; meet delivery schedules "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A general guideline used by many drivers is to allow two hours for every traveled",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": ["100  ", "128", "75", "150 "],
    "quesAnswer": "100"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "How can you estimate the range Of your vehicle? ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You can find that estimate listed your bill Of lading ",
      "Multiply the tan k capacity by the miles per gallon",
      "Multiply average speed by the vehicle tank capacity ",
      "Divide your idle time the miles per "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Multiply the tan k capacity by the miles per gallon"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following could affect your fuel usage estimations? ",
    "chapterId": 28,
    "quesOptions": [
      "City Driving ",
      "Driving in the mountains ",
      "All answers are correct",
      "Idling for an extended period Of time "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which activities are considered a safety-sensitive function?",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Loading a CMV ",
      "all answers are correct",
      "Driving a CMV ",
      "Waiting for assistance with a disabled "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A driver may not use alcohol during the hours before performing a safety-sensitive function ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": ["Four", "Eight", "Ten", "Six"],
    "quesAnswer": "Four"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "All drivers, prior to performing safety-sensitive functions for a motor carrier for the first time, must undergo what type Of pre-employment test, and have what type of result? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Alcohol test (failed)",
      "Drug test (positive) ",
      "Drug test (negative)",
      "iCal test (passed) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Drug test (negative)"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Who can order a test based on reasonable suspicion? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Your trained supervisor. based on intuition. hearsay, or a hunch ",
      "Any company employee who observes suspiciously reckless behavior ",
      "Any substance abuse professional ",
      "Your trained supervisor. based on direct observation"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Your trained supervisor. based on direct observation"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Alcohol testing is done in a private setting by a trained and qualified:",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Nurse practitioner Physician ",
      "Screening Test Technician Breath Alcohol Technician (BAT) ",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Screening Test Technician Breath Alcohol Technician (BAT) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If you initially test positive for drugs, what happens next? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A confirmatory drug test will be conducted",
      "You will be screened for alcohol use ",
      "Your COL will be revoked for 90 days ",
      "You will be sent to see a psychologist"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A confirmatory drug test will be conducted"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which actions are considered a refusal to test? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "All answers are correct ",
      "Failing to appear for any test within a reasonable time ",
      "Failing to remain at the testing Site until the test is complete "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All answers are correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "If you fail an alcohol test or test positive for drugs, you may not return to a safety- sensitive function until the return-to —duty process, including an evaluation by a has been completed. ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Breath Alcohol Technician (BAT) ",
      "Nurse practitioner (NP) ",
      "Screening Test Technician (STT) ",
      "Substance Abuse professional (SAP) "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Substance Abuse professional (SAP) "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following statements regarding alcohol use is true? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Alcohol does not affect your ability to think clearly. Alcohol can improve can coordination.",
      "Alcohol can Slow reaction time. Brain damage earn be a long-term effect Of alcohol abuse "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Alcohol can Slow reaction time. Brain damage earn be a long-term effect Of alcohol abuse "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What has a greater impact on your ability to drive, alcohol or drugs? ",
    "chapterId": 29,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Alcohol. Because use Of it is legal. it is easier to obtain in larger quantities ",
      "Both alcohol and drugs are equally as dangerous when you are under their influence and get behind the wheel",
      "Neither alcohol nor drugs will impact your ability to drive if consumed in moderation ",
      "Drugs. Because use of them is illegal, they Me harder to obtain "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Both alcohol and drugs are equally as dangerous when you are under their influence and get behind the wheel"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You must be at least to operate a CMV in interstate commerce ",
    "chapterId": 30,
    "quesOptions": [
      "18 years O Id ",
      "16 years old ",
      "25 years old ",
      "21 years Old "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "21 years Old "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A driver may be disqualified from driving a CMV if he or she: ",
    "chapterId": 30,
    "quesOptions": [
      "a CMV while smoking or vaping ",
      "spends too much time in the sleeper ",
      "left the scene of an accident with a ",
      "drove the CMV for personal use "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "left the scene of an accident with a "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following health conditions would negatively impact a driver's ability to safely operate a CMV? ",
    "chapterId": 30,
    "quesOptions": [
      "A missing limb ",
      "all answers are Correct ",
      "High blood pressure ",
      "Alcoholism "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are Correct "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A driver must undergo a physical examination once every ____ months at minimum, in order to be considered a qualified driver ",
    "chapterId": 30,
    "quesOptions": ["24 ", "48", "60", "72"],
    "quesAnswer": "24"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "A medical examiner must not qualify a driver who: ",
    "chapterId": 30,
    "quesOptions": [
      "has a medical condition that endangers the health and safety Of the driver the public, fails to meet a physical qualification requirement cited in the standards ",
      "passes their examination with no health conditions. Currently has a cold or flu that could "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "has a medical condition that endangers the health and safety Of the driver the public, fails to meet a physical qualification requirement cited in the standards "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Human trafficking is the use of ____ to cause a person to provide labor, services, or commercial sex ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": ["coercion, fraud. force", "flexibility, negotiating "],
    "quesAnswer": "coercion, fraud. force"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "This term describes a person who works in a private residence as a nanny, maid, or household help, and is not free to leave the property, is abused, and is underpaid, nor not paid at all ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Domestic ",
      "Forced trafficking ",
      "Sex trafficking ",
      "Forced labor"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Domestic "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following people is most at risk of becoming a victim Of human trafficking? ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Emma, a 15-year Old pregnant runaway ",
      "Bianca. a 42•year Old migrant from Nicaragua ",
      "All are equally at risk ",
      "Cameron. a 23-year Old gay male in a rural "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All are equally at risk "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Human traffickers are: ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "always to spot ",
      "branded or tattooed with a four-digit number",
      "engaged in the illegal transportation and(or) trade Of people",
      "Most often men between 50-69 years old"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "engaged in the illegal transportation and(or) trade Of people"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Most victims Of hurt-Ian trafficking: ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "are held hostage psychologically",
      "are hostage on the property of their trafficker ",
      "Know their captor",
      "have been kidnapped "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "are held hostage psychologically"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Victims Of human trafficking may: ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "appear to under the drugs or alcohol",
      "all answers are correct",
      "Travel with no personal possessions ",
      "avoid eye Contact When speaking "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "all answers are correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Body language can indicate a person is a victim Of trafficking. Which of the following would raise a red flag? ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Someone Who is not Very familiar With politics ",
      "Someone telling inappropriate jokes ",
      "A person who appears fearful or submissive ",
      "A Very outgoing and talkative person "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A person who appears fearful or submissive "
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following questions will help you determine if someone you are speaking with is a possible human trafficking victim? ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Do you have any pets? ",
      "Where do you live? ",
      "Do you know where you are right now? ",
      "What is your name? "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Do you know where you are right now? "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When contacting authorities, which information should you provide? ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Address description or location, Time and date, Detailed description Of any vehicles Or people involved.",
      "That's not necessary document ",
      "A list of possible outcomes if they don't "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "A list of possible outcomes if they don't "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What number do you call to report possible human trafficking to federal law ",
    "chapterId": 31,
    "quesOptions": [
      "1-866-DHS-2-ICE",
      "1-866-CALL-FED",
      "1-866-HUMAN-22",
      "1-866-STOP-NOW"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "1-866-DHS-2-ICE"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "CSA is a driver and carrier monitoring and evaluation system that is designed to:",
    "chapterId": 32,
    "quesOptions": [
      "rate drivers and on a daily basis ",
      "identify and intervene with drivers and carriers who are not in compliance with safety regulations",
      "recognize the safe actions Of drivers ",
      "keep track Of the Current location Of every CMV on the road "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "identify and intervene with drivers and carriers who are not in compliance with safety regulations"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Data collection, safety measurement, safety evaluation, and intervention are: ",
    "chapterId": 32,
    "quesOptions": [
      "statistical tools used to monitor drivers ",
      "BASICS of CSA system",
      "categories Of violations a carrier can be given",
      "major components Of the CSA system"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "major components Of the CSA system"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "CSA data is collected from which of the following sources? ",
    "chapterId": 32,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Driver job applications. phone calls' data ",
      "Law enforcement crash reports. Roadside inspections. FMCSA investigations "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Law enforcement crash reports. Roadside inspections. FMCSA investigations "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following violations fall under the unsafe Driving Basic? ",
    "chapterId": 32,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Driving after dark Without special permission",
      "Driving for too many hours in one day ",
      "Driving while intoxicated ",
      "Driving too close behind the vehicle ahead of you."
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Driving too close behind the vehicle ahead of you."
  },

  {
    "questionText": "The Hours-of-Service Compliance BASIC includes an out-of-service penalty. What other BASIC includes this penalty? ",
    "chapterId": 32,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Controlled Substances and Alcohol BASIC",
      "unsafe Driving BASIC ",
      "Hazardous Materials Compliance BASIC ",
      "Crash Indicator BASIC "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Hazardous Materials Compliance BASIC "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "You are loading a standard double with 20,000 pounds of cargo. Which of the following is the best way to distribute the weight between the two trailers? ",
    "chapterId": 33,
    "quesOptions": [
      "10,000 lbs. on lead trailer. 10.000 lbs. on rear",
      "18,000 lbs. on lead trailer. 2.000 lbs. on rear",
      "11,000 lbs. on lead trailer. 9000 on rear",
      "5,000 lbs. on lead trailer, 15.000 lbs. on rear"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "11,000 lbs. on lead trailer. 9000 on rear"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What is one maneuver you should never attempt while pulling triples? ",
    "chapterId": 33,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Backing into a loading dock area ",
      "Turning right at an intersection ",
      "Driving through a roundabout",
      "Driving down a grade of 15 degrees or more"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Backing into a loading dock area "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following statements about oversized vehicles is true?",
    "chapterId": 33,
    "quesOptions": [
      "You do not need a special to an oversized vehicle. Oversized vehicle are restricted highways that is actually depends on cargo type. ",
      "Requirements on type Of cargo, size, weight and state regulations. vehicles are restricted to designated highways."
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Requirements on type Of cargo, size, weight and state regulations. vehicles are restricted to designated highways."
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What type of cargo are low-clearance vehicles designed to haul? ",
    "chapterId": 33,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Loads With a high center-of-gravity. Loads that contain liquids  ",
      "Creator cubic capacity loads. Heavy. oversized cargo "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Creator cubic capacity loads. Heavy. oversized cargo "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "For vehicles with a high center Of gravity, how should the heaviest cargo be loaded for improved handling? ",
    "chapterId": 33,
    "quesOptions": [
      "High in the trailer and toward the back ",
      "Low in the trailer and toward the front ",
      "High in the trailer and toward the front ",
      "Low in the trailer and toward the back "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Low in the trailer and toward the front "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "To enter the country, Canada requires:",
    "chapterId": 34,
    "quesOptions": [
      "proof of identification and citizenship ",
      "you to become a Canadian citizen ",
      "no felony convictions for the prior ten years ",
      "immigration papers "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "proof of identification and citizenship "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following personal items must you declare at the Canadian border?",
    "chapterId": 34,
    "quesOptions": ["Fireworks", "All correct", "Ammunition", "Tobacco"],
    "quesAnswer": "All correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "In Canada, professional drivers are prohibited from having _____ in the cab of their vehicle under any circumstances ",
    "chapterId": 34,
    "quesOptions": ["alcohol ", "Tobacco", "Pets", "A radio"],
    "quesAnswer": "alcohol "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Before leaving for Canada, you need to ensure your vehicle registration, applicable safety certificates, fuel tax registration, and ______ are all in order",
    "chapterId": 34,
    "quesOptions": ["Permits", "Schedule", "DVIR", "Credentials"],
    "quesAnswer": "Permits"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which lanes should you use as you approach entry to the border station? ",
    "chapterId": 34,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Always take the lane with the shortest line",
      "American Pass lanes",
      "Any lane",
      "Designated commercial lanes"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Designated commercial lanes"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Why are rolling costs difficult to predict? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Sometimes they are fixed and other times they are not ",
      "They are always Changing ",
      "They are difficult to predict because they Stay the same all the time",
      "They use a substantial portion of revenue "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "They are always Changing "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What are the two main categories Of costs you should be familiar with as a truck driver? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Fuel and depreciation costs",
      "Rolling and fixed costs ",
      "Fixed and professional costs ",
      "Rolling and liability insurance costs"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Rolling and fixed costs "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following are fixed costs? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Fuel costs, Highway tolls, Contractors' payments",
      "Vehicle payments, Health insurance"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Vehicle payments, Health insurance"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Your driving habits can be one of the largest factors when it comes to: ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "driving technique ",
      "Progressive shifting",
      "fuel mileage ",
      "Driving strategies "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "fuel mileage "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "projecting a professional image on the road includes following all laws and regulations as well as practicing good driving habits, including: ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "passing in limited space ",
      "Following posted Speed limits ",
      "turning on your signal after Change lanes",
      "tailgating "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Following posted Speed limits"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What can you do to ensure you and your vehicle make a good impression in public? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Make Sure your vehicle is clean and well maintained ",
      "All correct",
      "Keep your hair combed and trim your beard or mustache if you have one",
      "Wear clean, appropriate Clothes for the workplace"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "All correct"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "What should you do if your delivery is going to arrive late? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Everyone understands late deliveries. there is no need to do anything ",
      "Drive faster so you can arrive as soon as possible",
      "Call the customer and let them know when you will to arrive ",
      "Ask the customer if they could meet "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Call the customer and let them know when you will to arrive "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Which Of the following are steps you can take when dealing With an angry customer? ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "Calmly let them know you are not happy they are taking their anger out on you ",
      "Don't speak with an angry customer until there is a mediator present ",
      "Apologize for the situation. even if it is not fault and to come up With a solution With the customer before "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "Apologize for the situation. even if it is not fault and to come up With a solution With the customer before "
  },

  {
    "questionText": "When applying for a job as a professional driver, much of the paperwork you will be required to fill out is mandated by. ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "the Department of Interior ",
      "the Department of Driver Expectations (DDE) ",
      "the potential employer ",
      "The federal motor carrier Regulations (FMCRS)"
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "The federal motor carrier Regulations (FMCRS)"
  },

  {
    "questionText": "Before you can operate a CMV you must pass: ",
    "chapterId": 35,
    "quesOptions": [
      "a physical exam. a pre-employment drug test. a road test ",
      "a food allergy test covid-19 test "
    ],
    "quesAnswer": "a physical exam. a pre-employment drug test. a road test "
  }
]
